lincolncenter.org 2019-12-12

# Lincoln Center

Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts, Inc. ("LCPA" or “we”) knows you care about your personal information.  This Privacy Policy (the “Policy”), which is part of our overall Terms and Conditions of Use, is designed to provide you with information about how we collect, use, and share the personal information that we may collect from you when you visit our websites, use our other online services, purchase our products, or otherwise interact with LCPA.  By accessing LCPA’s website or otherwise interacting with LCPA, you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this Privacy Policy.  If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, or any of the terms in the Terms and Conditions, you may not continue to access this site or otherwise interact with LCPA.

## **How We Collect Information**

We collect personal information from you when you visit our websites, register with us, use our other online services or otherwise interact with LCPA.  For example, we collect personal information from you when you sign up for a newsletter or make an online purchase.  In those instances, we will ask you for information such as your name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, certain demographic information and (if needed) credit card information.  As discussed below, we use this information to register you as a unique user, let you access personalized services, purchase tickets to shows or other events, and for other purposes.

For reasons such as improving and tailoring our products and services to you, we may use information received from other sources to supplement your account information.  For example, when visiting LCPA, we may collect publicly available information about your social media activity, including your location, in accordance with the Privacy Policies of your social media platforms.

## **How We Use Cookies**

A "cookie" is a text file, invoked by standard browser software, that we place on your hard drive when you visit our websites.  We use cookies and other similar technologies to enable our systems to, among other things, recognize your browser, track transactions, and allow you to navigate our websites and other online services without having to re-enter information.  By using LCPA’s website, you consent to the use of these cookies and other similar technologies.

We may receive and store certain other types of information through the use of cookies and similar technologies, such as the pages you link to from our websites.  This information helps us to understand how visitors use our websites and other online services, and helps to ensure that our websites, online services, and communications with you stay relevant and useful.

_We do not share personal information that we gather through cookies and similar technologies with third parties, except as set forth in this Policy._

Most browsers allow you to control cookies through their settings preferences. However, if you turn off the ability to use cookies and similar technologies, you may find that certain functionalities built into our websites and other online services do not work properly, or at all, and your overall user experience may be harmed.  For more information about cookies and similar technologies, including how to set your browser to reject cookies, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

## **Tracking Browsing History**

If you visit LCPA’s website simply to browse, we may collect general information about the way in which you use our website, including, but not limited to, the time and duration of visit, type of web browser used, the operating system or platform you are using, your IP address, and the websites from which you linked to us. We also may note whether and how you use the websites by recording site traffic patterns and clickstreams.

## **How We Use Personal Information**

We use personal information for a number of different activities.  For example, we may use personal information to communicate with you, to register you as a user, to allow you to make purchases, to ship tickets and other merchandise to you, to allow you to manage your subscriptions and memberships, to help you participate in special promotions and fundraising opportunities, to help you navigate our websites and other online services without re-entering information, to administer our websites and other online services, to comply with applicable laws, and as otherwise provided in this Policy.

Some of our programs use personal information to send updates and notices to registered users via e-mail. If you provide your mailing address or telephone number, we may also use that personal information to contact you when we have special offers, fundraising opportunities, or new services or events that we think may be of interest to you, or to provide you with updated information about us or our websites and online services.

In each of the cases described in this Policy, we process or share personal information only if: (a) we have your consent for doing so, (b) we believe we have a legitimate interest in doing so, (c) we need to process or share your data in order to perform or deliver the service you have requested, or (d) we are processing or sharing the data in compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject.

## **When We Share Your Personal Information**

We may engage third-parties in order to help us manage our websites and other online services, and to allow us to better serve our visitors and customers.  These may include third-party vendors engaged to analyze personal information for marketing purposes, so that we can provide you with more relevant and useful information, such as information about special offers, fundraising opportunities, or new services or events that may be of interest to you.  We make reasonable efforts to ensure that these parties only use personal information we provide to perform services for us and to protect such personal information in a commercially reasonable manner—these parties are prohibited from utilizing users’ personal information for other purposes.  Although we may share users’ personal information to improve operations, LCPA does not sell users’ personal information to third parties.  Further, LCPA does not share your personal information with third parties that are not service providers of LCPA without your consent.

We may occasionally make personal information available to select other organizations that may be of interest to you, including but not limited to non-profit arts organizations, affiliated organizations, companies or organizations with whom we have a contractual or sponsor relationship, or in connection with an asset transfer.  Among other organizations, LCPA may share our databases, including your personal information, with:  Chamber Music Society of Lincoln Center; Film at Lincoln Center; Jazz at Lincoln Center; Lincoln Center Theater; New York City Ballet; New York Philharmonic; The New York Public Library for the Performing Arts; Juilliard; The Metropolitan Opera; The School of American Ballet at Lincoln Center; and other similar entities.  We may also provide aggregated data to these and other organizations for marketing and fundraising purposes.  

The organizations that LCPA shares data with will only receive relevant visitor or customer information, which the visitor or customer has implicitly or explicitly consented to such disclosure.  When a user makes a purchase for an event produced by a third-party, LCPA may provide the third-party producer with the user’s purchase information, including the user’s name, address, phone number, and e-mail address.  Although we may make reasonable inquiries to determine that such other organizations maintain commercially reasonable privacy policies, we are not responsible for the handling of data or information of any such organization.

Our websites and online services may contain links to third-party websites and online services.  This privacy policy will not apply to any third-party websites or other online services.

We also partner with other organizations to provide you with content or services on a joint or “co-branded” basis using a co-branded website or online service with our co-branded partner displayed.  You should read the individual privacy policies of the co-branded websites or online services, as these policies may differ in some respects from this Policy.

## **Administration Of Our Website / Compliance With Law**

We may disclose personal information when we have reason to believe that disclosing it is necessary to identify, contact, or bring legal action against someone who may be violating our Terms and Conditions of Use or to protect the safety, property or other rights of our users or the public. In addition, we may disclose or access personal information for administrative and other purposes that we believe are necessary to develop, maintain, and improve our products and services. We also may disclose personal information if we believe in good faith that we are required to do so in order to comply with applicable law, a subpoena, or other legal process.

## **How You Can Review And Change Your Personal Information**

We encourage users to update and edit their personal information and keep it current by notifying us of any changes.  You can contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#15766066617a787067667067637c767055797c7b767a797b76707b6170673b7a677274) or by writing to us at:

Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts, Inc.  
Customer Service Department  
70 Lincoln Center Plaza, 9th Floor  
New York, NY 10023

Please include both your old and new contact information so that we can make the appropriate changes.

In certain jurisdictions, such as the European Union, you may have a right to access, correct, port, or erase the data we have about you, or to object to certain processing or sharing activities.  To make such a request or objection, contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#c1a2b4b2b5aeaca4b3b2a4b3b7a8a2a481ada8afa2aeadafa2a4afb5a4b3efaeb3a6). 

## **Opting-Out**

Our users are given the opportunity to “opt-out” of having their information used for purposes not directly related to that for which it was collected at any time.  Users who no longer wish to receive our promotional communications may opt-out of receiving these communications.   You can also opt-out if you don’t want us to use your personally identifiable information to contact you for marketing or solicitation purposes.  Users may also opt-out of having their information shared with third parties. 

To opt-out, users may contact LCPA at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#a3cacdc5cce3cfcacdc0cccfcdc0c6cdd7c6d18dccd1c4) or 212.875.5456.  Upon receiving an opt-out request, LCPA will delete or remove the pertinent information.

## **How We Protect Personal Information**

We take commercially reasonable steps to maintain the security of customer information, including personal information, via a variety of access controls, including password protection, electronic firewalls, and data encryption. However, no mode of transmission or method of storage can be completely secure, so we cannot guarantee the security of such information.

We will retain your personal information only for as long as we reasonably need it for legal or business purposes.  When we no longer need your personal information, we will securely delete or destroy it.

## **Other Organizations Featured On Our Website**

We may provide links to other websites and online services, but we are not responsible for the privacy policies, terms and conditions of use, or content of any such websites or online services. We encourage you to familiarize yourself with the privacy policies and terms and conditions of use of linked websites and online services. If you provide information – personal or otherwise – to such websites or online services, that information will be subject to their privacy policies.  Particular organizations we may feature include:  Chamber Music Society of Lincoln Center; Film at Lincoln Center; Jazz at Lincoln Center; Lincoln Center Theater; New York City Ballet; New York Philharmonic; The New York Public Library for the Performing Arts; Juilliard; The Metropolitan Opera; and The School of American Ballet at Lincoln Center.

## **Cross-Border Data Transfer**

We are located in the United States.  If you visit our websites or use our other online services, set up an account with us, purchase our products, or otherwise interact with LCPA, your personal information may be processed in the United States, where the laws regarding the treatment and use of personal information may be different from those in your country.  This Site is intended for use by individuals in the United States only.  However, if you are located in the European Union, we process your data only to the extent needed to provide you the services or products you have purchased, including by administering your account with us and keeping you updated about our events and news.

## **Children Under Thirteen Years of Age**

Online purchases through LCPA’s website may be made only by persons who are 18 years of age or older.  LCPA’s website is not directed to children under the age of 13, and children under 13 are prohibited from using LCPA’s website.  We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under thirteen (13) years of age.

## **Changes to This Privacy Policy**

We may revise this Policy from time to time. We encourage you to visit this page periodically to review our current Policy so that you will always know what personal information we collect and how we use and share it.

## **Whom To Contact If You Have Questions**

If you have any questions, please email us at: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#72111d071c01171e321e1b1c111d1e1c11171c0617005c1d0015) _.  _

Last updated November 22, 2019
